Now I'd like to talk about how to anchor your plant.
By this I mean, how to keep your plant from falling over.
Now if you've centered your plant correctly and you've firmed the soil around the plant.
And your container is not too big for the plant.
Hopefully, you shouldn't have too many problems with your plant being unstable.
But there are circumstances and there are types of plants.
Large and small.
Where you're going to have some problems with the plant.
Being in danger of falling over.
But sometimes, if a plant has a shallow root system.
Or the plant is very tall.
Or if the plant is placed in a very windy, high wind situation.
You may still have problems with your plant tipping over.
Or for example, indoors, if you're in a tight traffic area.
You've got a lot of people walking back and forth.
People might just run into the plant.
And it might be in danger of someone knocking it over.
So in order to make our plant more secure.
Especially, when we use a plastic container like this, too.
Sometimes the plant, just isn't heavy enough.
And it might tip over.
So to make it more secure, there is a number of techniques that we can use.
First of all, one of my favorite things to do.
Is use some rocks.
And have a whole bunch of different types of rocks.
Decorative rocks, large boulders.
Different sized rocks.
Smooth river rocks. We can throw these rocks, in with the plant. Lean it up, against the plant. And really stabilize the plant that way.
Rocks are great because they add weight to the plant.
And so they add weight to the container to prevent the container from tipping over.
Also they apply pressure to the roots.
So that the plant won't tip over so easily.
Or we can also use little ornaments like this.
And broken bricks.
Also we have some wooden sticks.
You can stick a wooden stick in there.
And tie the plant with some green plant tape or some string.
What I have here is some nice bamboo.
I've cut some bamboo sticks.
And you can also use a bamboo stick with a little string or some wire.
To hold your plant in place.
Now indoors or sometimes outdoors, too.
You can use a trellis.
Trellis is another great option.
Or another really great technique is to simply prop the plant up.
So that it's leaning against the wall.
Sometimes, if you just lean your plant up against the wall.
It provides some extra support.
So basically, these are some great techniques that you can use to anchor your plant.